ALL CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS, EVENTS, AND LOCATIONS IN THIS SHOW ARE FICTITIOUS
모든 캐릭터, 조직, 이벤트, 이 쇼의 위치는 허구입니다.
Something's wrong,
뭔가 문제가 발생했습니다.
isn't it?
그렇지 않나요?
Yes.
예.
Something's wrong
문제가 발생했습니다.
but I can't even believe it
하지만 난 그걸 믿을 수도 없어
because it feels too unreal.
너무 비현실적으로 느껴지기 때문이죠.
I think I know what it is.
나는 그것이 무엇인지 알 것 같아요.
No.
아니요.
You really don't know.
당신은 정말로 모른다.
I think I know what it is!
내 생각엔 그게 뭔지 알 것 같아!
You want to kill those two bastards.
당신은 그 두 놈을 죽이고 싶어합니다.
Professor Seo is cheating on you!
서교수님이 바람을 피우고 계시네요!
It's raining!
비가 온다!
Hurry up and close it.
서둘러서 닫으세요.
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
-Why isn't it working? -Hurry up!
- 왜 작동하지 않나요? -서둘러요!
I'm trying!
노력 중이에요!
You can't even close the roof of your own car?
닫지도 못하잖아 당신의 차 지붕?
I opened it for the first time today!
오늘 처음 오픈했어요!
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
It's cold!
춥다!
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
This isn't the time to be laughing!
지금은 웃을 때가 아니다!
It's cold!
춥다!
Come on, stop laughing!
어서, 웃지 마세요!
How badly did you two fight to end up like this?
둘이 얼마나 심하게 싸웠는지 이렇게 끝나려고?
How will you even draw in this state? Your entrance exams are around the corner!
이 상태에서는 어떻게 그림을 그릴 수 있나요? 여러분의 입학 시험이 코앞으로 다가왔습니다!
-What? -You said you're done letting off steam!
-무엇? - 이제 화 풀었다고 하더군요!
You should've just ignored her, not fought her!
넌 그냥 그녀를 무시했어야 했어 그녀와 싸운 게 아니야!
Are you saying I should've held back when she grabbed my hair?
내가 참았어야 했다는 거야? 그 사람이 내 머리를 잡았을 때?
What?
무엇?
Why should I move academies?
왜 학원을 옮겨야 하나요?
She keeps telling me to move!
계속 움직이라고 하더군요!
That brat is treating me like I'm some home-wrecker too!
그 새끼가 날 치료하고 있어 나도 집 파괴자 인 것처럼!
I'm leaving for the day.
나는 오늘 떠날 예정이다.
-Goodbye. -Great work today.
-안녕히 가세요. -오늘 정말 수고했어요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
I-rang.
아이링.
EPISODE 11
에피소드 11
Honestly.
솔직히.
Thankfully, I don't think it'll scar.
다행히 흉터는 안날 것 같아요.
Are you hurt anywhere else?
다른 곳은 다치셨나요?
What on earth happened?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어난 걸까요?
Are you getting bullied in school or something?
학교에서 왕따를 당하고 있나요? 아니면 뭔가?
You and your friends will be adults soon. They should know better.
당신과 당신의 친구들은 곧 성인이 될 것입니다. 그들은 더 잘 알아야 합니다.
Why would they do this to you?
그들이 당신에게 왜 이런 짓을 할까요?
Who did this to you?
누가 당신에게 이런 짓을 했나요?
-Auntie Mi-hee. -Yes.
-미희 아줌마. -예.
I feel so bad for my mom.
엄마가 너무 안타까워요.
Your mom?
당신의 엄마?
MI-HEE: I-RANG CAME TO VISIT MY CLINIC…
미희: 아이랑이 내 진료소를 방문했어요…
I-RANG CAME TO VISIT MY CLINIC
아이랑이 내 진료소를 방문했어요
I'M GOING TO TAKE HER HOME, SO DON'T WORRY
내가 그 사람을 집에 데려갈 테니 걱정하지 마세요.
Who is it?
누구입니까?
There's non-alcoholic beer too.
무알콜 맥주도 있어요.
On my grandma's birthday,
할머니 생신날,
my family got together for dinner.
우리 가족은 저녁 식사를 위해 함께 모였습니다.
It was at a hotel.
호텔에 있었어요.
And I coincidentally saw Professor Seo there.
그리고 우연히 봤는데 거기 서교수님.
I saw who the other woman was too.
다른 여자도 누군지 봤어요.
When I was in middle school,
제가 중학교 시절,
my father did the same thing.
나의 아버지도 똑같은 일을 하셨다.
My mother had depression after that happened.
어머니가 우울증을 앓고 계셨어요 그 일이 일어난 후.
She suffered for more than ten years.
그녀는 10년 넘게 고통을 겪었습니다.
So I kind of know how you feel.
그래서 나는 당신이 어떤 기분인지 어느 정도 알고 있습니다.
Something like this can be so destructive…
이런 일은 매우 파괴적일 수 있습니다…
that it can ruin someone.
누군가를 망칠 수 있다는 것.
How was it for you?
당신은 어땠나요?
Did you wish that
당신은 그것을 원했나요?
your mother and father would get divorced?
네 엄마 아빠가 이혼하실 거야?
At the time,
당시,
I thought Mom's hatred toward Dad was what kept her going.
엄마가 아빠를 미워하는 줄 알았는데 그녀를 계속 나아가게 한 것은 바로 그것이었다.
If they got divorced,
만약 그들이 이혼했다면,
I thought my mom would lose the only thing that gave her the will to live.
엄마가 하나만 잃어버릴 줄 알았는데 그것이 그녀에게 살아갈 의지를 주었습니다.
So I told my dad…
그래서 아빠한테 말했어요...
that if he divorced my mom,
만약 그 사람이 우리 엄마와 이혼했다면,
I would throw myself from the roof.
나는 지붕에서 몸을 던질 것입니다.
I threatened him.
나는 그를 위협했다.
I know you keep to yourself.
나는 당신이 스스로를 지키고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
So thank you for trying
노력해 주셔서 감사합니다.
to comfort me.
나를 위로하기 위해.
I'm not trying to comfort you.
나는 당신을 위로하려는 것이 아닙니다.
It's just…
그것은 단지…
these things happen.
이런 일이 일어납니다.
More often than we think.
우리가 생각하는 것보다 더 자주.
Try to get some sleep.
잠을 좀 자도록 노력하세요.
Thank you for the drive today.
오늘 운전해주셔서 감사합니다.
Sure.
확신하는.
Actually…
사실…
I have something to confess.
고백할 게 있어요.
The two of you.
너희 둘.
Jung-min.
정민.
I know that you're dating
나는 당신이 데이트하고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다
my son.
내 아들.
From the looks of it,
겉으로 보면,
you two suit each other.
너희 둘은 서로 어울리잖아.
COLON AND RECTAL SURGERY SPECIALIST SEO IN-HO
결장 및 직장 수술 전문의 서인호
OUT OF OFFICE
부재중
-Please check the consultation request. -Okay.
- 상담요청 내용을 확인해주세요. -좋아요.
Do you think you can work today?
오늘 일할 수 있을 것 같아?
I have to.
그래야 해요.
Working is the only thing I can do right now.
일하는 것이 유일한 일이다 지금 당장 할 수 있어요.
-You see this, right? -Yes.
- 이거 보이죠? -예.
This part seems to be causing the issue.
이 부분이 문제를 일으키는 것 같습니다.
-You said she draws right? -Yes.
- 그 사람이 그림을 그린다고 했죠? -예.
Even when she gets out of the cast, her arm's range of motion can be limited.
그녀가 출연진에서 나왔을 때에도 팔의 움직임 범위가 제한될 수 있습니다.
And her wrist might not move the way she wants.
그리고 그녀의 손목은 움직이지 않을지도 몰라 그녀가 원하는 방식으로.
It'll take around three to six months
3~6개월 정도 걸릴 것 같아요
for the nerves to recover.
신경이 회복되도록.
How would you know that when you raised your kids in comfort?
그걸 어떻게 알겠어요? 아이들을 편안하게 키웠을 때?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about Seung-hi working at our hospital.
말하지 않아서 미안해 우리 병원에서 일하는 승희에 대해서요.
But I already explained why I didn't tell you.
하지만 난 이미 설명했지 내가 왜 당신에게 말하지 않았는지.
And I also just learned that I-rang and Seung-hi's daughter are friends.
그리고 나도 방금 내가 전화했다는 걸 알았어 그리고 승희 딸은 친구예요.
Could you tell me where you bought that bracelet?
나에게 말해줄래? 그 팔찌는 어디서 샀어요?
My husband bought it for me, so I don't know where he got it.
남편이 사줬는데, 그래서 그 사람이 그걸 어디서 얻었는지 모르겠어요.
-Where is Choi Seung-hi right now? -Sorry?
-최승희는 지금 어디에 있나요? -죄송합니다?
She'll be in the seminar room. All the professors today…
그녀는 세미나실에 있을 거예요. 오늘 교수님들 다...
Didn't she just address her by name only?
방금 이름만 부르지 않았나요?
I think she said, "Where's Choi Seung-hi?"
'최승희는 어디 있지?'라고 말한 것 같아요.
Come on, no way.
어서, 절대 안돼.
Any updates on the academic research fund that we applied for?
학술연구비 관련 최신 소식 우리가 신청한 거요?
We plan to apply for a collaborative multidisciplinary team study.
공동으로 신청할 예정입니다. 다학제적 팀 연구.
So we are preparing a joint research plan
그래서 공동연구 계획을 준비 중입니다.
with the infectious diseases and pulmonology departments.
전염병으로 호흡기과.
We'll need to schedule regular meetings.
정기적인 회의 일정을 잡아야 할 것 같아요.
Sure. Meetings are one thing.
확신하는. 회의는 한 가지입니다.
But please share the progress via email…
하지만 진행 상황을 이메일로 공유해주세요…
Yes, what is it?
응, 그게 뭐야?
Professor Choi.
최 교수님.
I need a word with you.
당신과 할 말이 필요해요.
If it's not urgent, let's talk later. I'm in the middle of--
급한 일이 아니면 나중에 얘기하자. 난 지금--
It's urgent.
긴급합니다.
Or shall we talk here?
아니면 여기서 얘기할까?
-What is it? -Let's go to your office.
-이게 뭐죠? - 사무실로 가자.
Tell him to come.
그에게 오라고 ​​말하세요.
Seo In-ho.
서인호.
Did you not hear me?
내 말을 못 들었나요?
Tell Seo In-ho
서인호에게 말해요
to come here.
여기로 오려고.
Right this instant.
바로 이 순간.
Call him.
그에게 전화하세요.
Hey.
여기요.
I just finished an outpatient appointment. I have some time.
방금 외래 진료 예약을 마쳤어요. 시간이 좀 있어요.
To your office?
사무실로 가시나요?
Don't ask and just come. You'll know when you get here.
묻지 말고 그냥 오세요. 여기 오면 알게 될 거예요.
Come here right now.
지금 당장 여기로 오세요.
Unless you want
당신이 원하지 않는 한
the whole hospital to be talking about your affair with Choi Seung-hi.
병원 전체에 대해 이야기하고 싶어 최승희와의 불륜.
PROFESSOR'S OFFICE
교수실
FAMILY MEDICINE SPECIALIST CHOI SEUNG-HI IN OFFICE
가정의학 전문의 최승희 사무실에서
OUT OF OFFICE
부재중
-Honey. -Shut up.
-여보. -입 다물어.
Confirm something for me.
확인해 주세요.
I-rang's friend, Eun-seo.
이랑의 친구 은서.
Is your daughter
당신의 딸인가요?
Seo In-ho's daughter?
서인호 딸?
Honey, the thing is…
여보, 문제는…
That's right. She is In-ho's daughter.
맞습니다. 인호의 딸이다.
We met coincidentally at a hospital in Chicago
우리는 우연히 만났어요 시카고의 한 병원에서
where In-ho and I trained.
인호와 내가 훈련했던 곳.
Eun-seo was conceived then and I gave birth to her.
그때 잉태된 은서 그리고 나는 그녀를 낳았습니다.
But I didn't keep seeing her.
하지만 나는 그녀를 계속 만나지 않았습니다.
Three years ago, when Seung-hi came back to Korea and came to this hospital,
3년 전 승희가 돌아왔을 때 한국에 와서 이 병원에 왔는데,
we got close again…
우리 또 친해졌어…
Did you have no one to share your love story with?
아무도 없었나요? 당신의 사랑 이야기를 공유하고 싶습니까?
You two are taking turns talking
둘이 번갈아 가며 얘기하고 있어요
as if you're so eager to get the next word in.
마치 네가 그렇게 열심인 것처럼 다음 단어를 입력하려면
Sure, so the two of you
응, 그럼 너희 둘이서
are in love?
사랑에 빠졌어?
I hope it lasts forever.
나는 그것이 영원히 지속되기를 바랍니다.
It's not that. The truth is…
그게 아닙니다. 진실은…
-We already decided to break up… -Who said we would?
-이미 헤어지기로 결정했는데… - 누가 그러겠다고 했나요?
I don't plan on breaking up.
나는 헤어질 생각이 없습니다.
Whether you two break up
둘이 헤어지든 말든
or live together for years on end
아니면 수년 동안 함께 살거나
has nothing to do with me anymore.
더 이상 나와 관련이 없습니다.
I restarted my residency after 20 years, and I'm going to complete it.
20년 만에 레지던트를 다시 시작했는데, 그리고 나는 그것을 완료할 것이다.
As for you two,
너희 둘에 관해서는,
don't disgrace me or my son.
나와 내 아들을 욕되게 하지 마십시오.
And Choi Seung-hi.
그리고 최승희.
Quit this hospital.
이 병원을 그만두세요.
You have other hospitals you can go to.
갈 수 있는 다른 병원도 있어요.
Don't you come from a rich family?
당신은 부유한 집안 출신이 아니신가요?
I know that the two of you have been doing all you can
난 알아요 너희 둘이 당신이 할 수 있는 모든 일을 해왔어
to get me to quit.
나를 그만 두려고.
Those cheap tricks won't work anymore, so you quit.
그 값싼 트릭 더 이상 일이 안 되니까 그만 두세요.
You have a month.
한 달 남았습니다.
Quit within a month
한달 안에 그만둬라
and get out of my sight.
그리고 내 눈앞에서 사라져라.
And you, Seo In-ho!
그리고 당신, 서인호!
You lie low and wait.
당신은 누워서 기다리세요.
I'm still thinking about what I should do with you.
아직도 생각 중이야 내가 당신을 어떻게 해야 하는지.
When you said we should take some time to think,
당신이 말했을 때 우리는 생각할 시간을 좀 가져야 해요
I thought you meant we should break up.
우리 헤어져야 한다는 뜻인 줄 알았는데.
I guess that's what you wanted to hear.
그 말이 듣고 싶었던 것 같아요.
I guess you were so desperate for me to give up on you.
너무 절망적이었나 봐 내가 당신을 포기하기 위해.
It's not that.
그게 아닙니다.
Then going forward…
그럼 앞으로…
Do we really need to break up?
우리 정말 헤어져야 하는 걸까?
I think you'll be a free man at last.
내 생각엔 당신이 마침내 자유인이 될 것 같아요.
-A free man? -Don't you think she'll divorce you soon?
- 자유인이요? - 그 사람이 곧 당신과 이혼할 것 같지 않아요?
This…
이…
How much does I-rang know?
아이랑은 얼마나 알고 있나요?
Tell me the truth!
진실을 말해주세요!
She knows everything.
그녀는 모든 것을 알고 있습니다.
What about Jung-min?
정민이는요?
-He knows. -What?
-그는 알고 있어요. -무엇?
Mother knows too.
어머니도 알고 계십니다.
Look what you've done.
당신이 무슨 짓을했는지보세요.
And you dared to act all high and mighty in front of me
그리고 당신은 감히 내 앞에서 높고 위대하게 행동하는 것
after everything you've done?
네가 한 모든 일 후에?
My children are so pitiful to have you as their father, you bastard!
우리 아이들이 너무 불쌍해요 너를 그들의 아버지로 삼다니, 이 개자식아!
Be quiet.
조용히 하세요.
Why did you make a fool out of me when the whole family already knew?
왜 나를 바보로 만들었나요? 온 가족이 이미 알고 있었을 때?
Why was I the only one who didn't know?
왜 나만 몰랐던 걸까?
The kids didn't want you to know!
아이들은 당신이 알기를 원하지 않았습니다!
They didn't want you to be in shock when you haven't fully recovered yet.
그들은 당신이 충격에 빠지는 것을 원하지 않았습니다 아직 완전히 회복되지 않았을 때.
Live the rest of your life…
남은 인생을 살아라…
atoning to the kids.
아이들에게 속죄합니다.
You horrible bastard!
이 끔찍한 놈아!
How could you do this?
어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있었나요?
How could you do this to our kids?
어떻게 우리 아이들에게 이런 짓을 할 수 있나요?
Dr. Kim, hello.
김 박사님, 안녕하세요.
-You went to see your baby again? -Yes.
-또 아기를 보러 갔나요? -예.
It's a relief that both of you are safe.
두 분 모두 무사하셔서 다행입니다.
I was really shocked when I heard you had to give birth right away
듣고 정말 충격받았어요 넌 당장 출산했어야 했어
due to amniorrhexis.
양수 부정맥으로 인해.
My baby was the one who pulled through.
내 아기가 이겨낸 사람이었습니다.
She's recovering well like her nickname "Little Miss Strong."
그녀는 잘 회복하고 있어요 그녀의 별명 "Little Miss Strong"처럼요.
How admirable.
정말 감탄스럽습니다.
I heard you're being discharged.
당신이 퇴원한다는 소식을 들었습니다.
Yes.
예.
And my baby is going to be discharged in about two weeks.
그리고 우리 아기는 퇴원할 거예요 약 2주 후에요.
Are you really just going to leave without getting treated?
정말 그냥 떠나실 건가요? 치료도 못 받고?
Yes.
예.
I'll go home, and my mom will take care of me.
나는 집에 갈 것이다. 그러면 엄마가 나를 돌봐줄 거예요.
Once the baby comes home,
아기가 집에 오면,
I'll feed it formula, put it to sleep, and bathe it.
분유를 먹일게요 재우고 목욕시키세요.
That's what I want to do.
그것이 내가 하고 싶은 일이다.
I won't be able to do that once I start treatment.
나는 그렇게 할 수 없을 것이다 일단 치료를 시작합니다.
There's no hope anyway.
어쨌든 희망이 없습니다.
Be good to your mom. Becoming a mom is hard.
엄마에게 잘 지내세요. 엄마가 되는 것은 어렵다.
I just visited the baby.
방금 아기를 방문했습니다.
She's gotten chubbier since yesterday.
그녀는 어제부터 더 통통해졌습니다.
When I called out her nickname,
내가 그녀의 별명을 불렀을 때,
she looked at me as if she recognized--
그녀는 나를 알아보았다는 듯이 나를 쳐다보았다.
I don't want to hear it. Stop.
나는 그것을 듣고 싶지 않습니다. 멈추다.
No one is happy to see your baby.
아기를 보고 기뻐할 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
Mom.
엄마.
Stop hating my baby.
내 아기를 미워하지 마세요.
If I'm gone, all she will have is you and Dad.
내가 사라지면, 그녀에게 남은 것은 당신과 아빠뿐입니다.
You and Dad will have to raise the baby.
당신과 아빠는 아기를 키워야 할 것입니다.
You raise the baby.
당신은 아기를 키운다.
You're responsible for your child, not me!
당신의 아이에 대한 책임은 내가 아닌 당신에게 있습니다!
You should be the one to do everything from her 100th-day celebration party
당신은 모든 일을 하는 사람이 되어야 합니다 그녀의 100일 축하 파티에서
and her first birthday, to taking her to her first day of school!
그리고 그녀의 첫 번째 생일, 그녀를 학교 첫날에 데려가는 것!
If you don't, I don't want to see that kid.
그렇지 않으면, 나는 그 아이를 보고 싶지 않아요.
Okay.
좋아요.
I'll do all of that, okay?
그건 내가 다 해줄게, 알았지?
Yes, is this Seocho Police Station?
네, 여기가 서초경찰서인가요?
I want to find the family I was separated from as a child.
가족을 찾고 싶어요 나는 어렸을 때 헤어졌다.
How do I register my DNA?
내 DNA를 어떻게 등록하나요?
Are you free after work?
퇴근 후에 시간 있어요?
That's new.
그것은 새로운 것입니다.
You've never once asked me if I have time or if I want to meet first.
넌 한 번도 나한테 물어본 적 없어 시간이 있으면, 아니면 먼저 만나고 싶으면.
I'm the one who clings to you, appeases you, and gets upset.
나는 당신에게 매달리는 사람입니다. 당신을 달래기도 하고 화를 내기도 합니다.
Even when I do that, you meet me once every five times.
그렇게 할 때도, 다섯 번에 한 번씩 만나요.
This doesn't seem like a normal relationship.
이건 아닌 것 같아 정상적인 관계.
Sure.
확신하는.
If that's what you think, it must be true.
당신이 그렇게 생각한다면 그것은 사실일 것입니다.
Being stubborn is in your nature. Why are you agreeing with me on this?
완고한 것은 당신의 본성입니다. 왜 이것에 대해 나에게 동의합니까?
Shouldn't you be lecturing me about how relationships can differ?
나한테 강의를 해야 하지 않나? 관계는 어떻게 다를 수 있습니까?
What's the point when things are ending?
일이 끝나면 무슨 의미가 있나요?
But we should at least end things properly.
하지만 우리는해야 적어도 일을 제대로 끝내십시오.
We'll still be seeing each other.
우리는 계속해서 만날 것입니다.
I have something to tell you too.
나도 당신에게 할 말이 있어요.
Let's meet after work.
퇴근 후에 만나자.
D&J ART ACADEMY
디앤제이 미술 아카데미
-Seo I-rang. -Mom!
-서이랑. -엄마!
Were you waiting long?
오래 기다리셨나요?
I didn't wait that long.
나는 그렇게 오래 기다리지 않았다.
You were working so hard.
정말 열심히 일하셨어요.
-You saw? -Of course!
-봤어? -물론!
Let's eat something good.
좋은 것 좀 먹자.
-Great!
-엄청난!
Do you have something to say?
할 말 있어?
I…
나는…
-found out. -About what?
-알았어요. -무엇에 대해서요?
About Dad.
아빠에 대해서.
And about your friend Eun-seo too.
그리고 네 친구 은서에 대해서도.
It must've been so painful.
너무 고통스러웠나 봐요.
You couldn't even tell me.
당신은 나에게 말할 수도 없었습니다.
It felt strange.
이상한 느낌이 들었습니다.
To find I have a sibling other than Jung-min.
나에게 형제가 있다는 걸 알아내려면 정민 외.
There is someone else in this world who calls my dad "Dad."
다른 사람이 있어요 아빠를 아빠라고 부르는 이 세상에서.
And that person is Eun-seo.
그리고 그 사람은 은서입니다.
I'm sorry
미안해요
for making you worry about something other kids don't have to go through.
당신이 뭔가에 대해 걱정하게 만들어서 다른 아이들은 겪을 필요가 없습니다.
Did you tell Jung-min?
정민한테 말했어?
That you know everything?
당신은 모든 것을 알고 있습니까?
He is an adult, so I'm not worried about him.
그는 성인이고, 그래서 나는 그에 대해 걱정하지 않습니다.
I'm grown up too, so don't worry about me.
나도 어른이니까 걱정하지 마세요.
And do what you want.
그리고 당신이 원하는 것을하십시오.
Whatever that may be, I don't care.
그것이 무엇이든 나는 상관하지 않습니다.
No, I'm okay with it.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
I feel so reassured
정말 안심이 되네요
to have you guys.
너희들을 가지려고.
You should hurry up and eat.
빨리 가서 먹어야 해요.
I'll end up eating everything.
결국 다 먹게 되네요.
I'll eat.
나는 먹을 것이다.
Okay, is the
알았어, 그렇지?
It's good.
좋다.
Eun-seo, what's wrong?
은서 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
How will I take the early admissions exam with this arm?
조기입학시험은 어떻게 치르나요? 이 팔로?
There are regular admissions.
정기모집이 있습니다.
You won't be wearing the cast then.
그러면 캐스트를 착용하지 않을 것입니다.
You really know nothing.
당신은 정말 아무것도 몰라요.
For regular admissions,
정기전형의 경우,
you can only apply to either Hanguk University or Hongin University.
둘 중 하나만 신청할 수 있습니다. 한국대학교나 홍인대학교.
Then just apply to one.
그럼 하나만 신청하세요.
I never pressured you about college.
나는 대학에 관해 당신에게 압력을 가한 적이 없습니다.
Seo I-rang can apply to both universities, unlike me!
서이랑 신청 가능 나와는 달리 두 대학 모두에!
I can't even compete in early admissions, and I can only apply to one school.
수시모집 경쟁도 못 하고, 그리고 한 학교에만 지원할 수 있어요.
Eun-seo.
은서.
I'd rather die than go to a less prestigious school than her!
차라리 죽는 게 낫겠어 그 사람보다 덜 명문인 학교에 가!
I'll lose some of my touch after being in a cast for two months.
난 내 감각을 좀 잃게 될 거야 두 달 동안 깁스를 한 후.
What do I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
You won't lose your touch.
당신은 당신의 손길을 잃지 않을 것입니다.
You're…
당신은…
going to do well.
잘할 거야.
Why do I have to get things taken away?
왜 물건을 빼앗아야 합니까?
From Dad to opportunities.
아빠에서 기회로.
Why is it always me?
왜 항상 나야?
Is there really a need to meet like this to break up?
정말로 필요한가? 이렇게 만나서 헤어지려고?
I have something to say.
할 말이 있어요.
Say it.
말해 보세요.
I found out that Professor Seo is having an affair.
서교수님을 알게 됐어요 불륜을 저지르고 있어요.
And I learned that Dr. Cha found out
그리고 차 박사님이 알아내셨다는 걸 알게 됐어요
about his affair.
그의 불륜에 대해.
It's embarrassing to have found out all these fine details about your family,
알게 된 게 부끄러워요 가족에 대한 모든 세세한 정보,
but I thought I should let you know.
하지만 알려줘야겠다고 생각했어요.
I thought you should know if you didn't already.
난 당신이 알아야 한다고 생각했어요 아직 하지 않았다면.
Did you not know?
몰랐나요?
I knew about my father's affair.
나는 아버지의 불륜을 알고 있었다.
But I didn't know that my mom knew.
하지만 엄마가 알고 계실 줄은 몰랐어요.
-It must be hard for you. -It's something I have to handle.
-힘드실 텐데요. -내가 처리해야 할 일이에요.
Are you done?
끝났나요?
I'll go now.
나는 지금 갈 것이다.
Seo In-ho, that bastard.
서인호, 그 새끼.
He doesn't look like it,
그 사람은 그렇게 보이지 않는데,
but it seems like he has incredibly strong instincts to reproduce.
하지만 그 사람은 그런 것 같아 재생산 본능이 엄청나게 강하다.
If not, how can he maintain two families and have a secret love child
그렇지 않다면 어떻게 두 가족을 부양할 수 있겠습니까? 그리고 비밀스러운 사랑의 아이가 있어요
in this day and age?
요즘 시대에?
Sure.
확신하는.
Tell the whole world about my husband maintaining two families.
전 세계에 알려주세요 남편이 두 가족을 부양하고 있어요.
What? Do you want me to give you a loudspeaker?
무엇? 당신은 나를 원합니까? 너한테 확성기를 주려고?
What on earth do people see in him?
도대체 사람들은 그에게서 무엇을 보나요?
What gives him the right to be loved by two great women?
무엇이 그에게 권리를 주는가 두 명의 위대한 여성에게 사랑을 받으려면?
Is Seo In-ho good in bed?
서인호는 침대에서 잘 자나요?
Jeez, honestly.
이런, 솔직히.
What? I need to know that to explain this fiasco!
무엇? 난 그걸 알아야 해 이 실패를 설명하기 위해!
Hey!
여기요!
Do you think I'd remember? We slept in separate rooms for ten years.
내가 기억할 것 같아? 우리는 10년 동안 서로 다른 방에서 잤습니다.
Right, you're Candy.
그렇죠, 당신은 캔디예요.
So what are you going to do now?
그럼 이제 무엇을 할 건가요?
What can I really do?
나는 정말로 무엇을 할 수 있는가?
We'll fight and pester each other,
서로 싸우고 괴롭히고
and in the end, we'll get divorced.
그리고 결국 우리는 이혼하게 될 거예요.
And who would benefit from that?
그리고 누가 그로부터 이익을 얻을 것인가?
So?
그래서?
What will you do now?
이제 무엇을 하시겠습니까?
Are you going to live with Jeong-suk?
정숙이랑 같이 살래?
Or will you divorce her and go to that woman?
아니면 그 사람과 이혼할 것인가? 그리고 그 여자한테 가?
Not in front of the kids.
아이들 앞에서는 안돼요
We should be aware of your decision too.
우리도 귀하의 결정을 알아야 합니다.
So are you going to marry that woman?
그럼 그 여자랑 결혼할 거예요?
Hey, don't say such nonsense.
아, 그런 말도 안되는 소리 하지 마세요.
You're really the worst.
당신은 정말 최악이에요.
It's better to give up on one side and devote yourself to the other.
한쪽으로 포기하는 것이 낫다 그리고 다른 사람에게 헌신하십시오.
This is the worst thing to do to Mom and that woman.
이건 엄마한테 하는 최악의 짓이야 그리고 그 여자.
Unlike what you think, it's not an easy decision.
여러분이 생각하는 것과는 달리, 쉬운 결정은 아닙니다.
You can't speak so recklessly about grown-ups' matters.
당신은 그것에 대해 너무 함부로 말할 수 없습니다 어른들의 문제.
So are you going to get divorced?
그럼 이혼할 건가요?
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
I…
나는…
don't want to get divorced.
이혼하고 싶지 않아요.
Try to walk.
걸어보세요.
This is the first time I walked out of a bar on my own
이번이 처음이에요 나는 혼자서 술집에서 나왔다
because I was embarrassed.
부끄러웠기 때문이죠.
How did you never grow up?
어떻게 성장하지 못했나요?
You're the same as you were in college.
당신은 대학 시절과 똑같습니다.
Fine, you're the mature one. You're the true adult here. Happy?
좋아요, 당신은 어른이군요. 당신은 여기서 진정한 어른입니다. 행복하다?
I am!
그래요!
-I'm tired. -Sit.
-피곤해요. -앉다.
Jeez, why did you drink so much?
이런, 왜 그렇게 많이 마셨어?
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
I'm surrounded by foolish men like that.
내 주변에는 그런 어리석은 남자들이 있다.
You would think their wives would not be great, right?
당신은 생각할 것이다 그들의 아내는 별로 좋지 않을 겁니다. 그렇죠?
But no, they're all decent.
하지만 아니요, 모두 괜찮습니다.
Do you think those women aren't getting a divorce because they have no pride?
그 여자들이 이해받지 못한다고 생각하시나요? 자존심이 없어서 이혼?
They just live with it.
그들은 단지 그것과 함께 살고 있습니다.
You live an exciting life on your own.
당신은 스스로 흥미로운 삶을 살고 있습니다.
And you're telling me not to get a divorce?
그리고 당신은 나에게 말하고 있어요 이혼하지 않으려면?
My life is lousy.
내 인생은 형편 없다.
You just don't know how thankful you should be for that lousy life.
얼마나 감사한지 모르실 거에요 당신은 그 형편없는 삶을 살아야합니다.
Honestly,
솔직히,
if hell exists,
지옥이 존재한다면,
then that place
그럼 그 곳
would be in here.
여기 있을 거예요.
Anyway, I'm jealous of that too.
아무튼 나도 그게 부럽다.
So just live your life.
그러니 그냥 당신의 삶을 살아보세요.
You want me to keep living like this?
내가 계속 이렇게 살길 바라는 거야?
I bought you a plant in college that cost 5,000 won.
대학 때 식물을 사줬어 그건 5,000원이에요.
You still managed to keep it healthy even after 20 years.
그래도 건강하게 잘 지내셨네요 20년이 지나도.
You could never let go of any relationship you have,
넌 절대 놓을 수 없어 당신이 어떤 관계를 갖고 있든,
whether it be with a plant or with an animal.
식물이 있든 없든 아니면 동물과 함께.
Do you think you can leave Seo In-ho?
서인호를 떠날 수 있을 것 같나요?
Fine.
괜찮은.
If that makes you happy,
그것이 당신을 행복하게 만든다면,
I'll welcome that decision with my arms and legs--
나는 그 결정을 환영할 것이다 내 팔과 다리로--
Hey!
이봐!
-I'll do a shoulder dance too. -Jeez, honestly.
-어깨춤도 춰요. - 이런, 솔직히.
Still…
아직도…
regardless of everything,
모든 것과 상관없이,
if breaking up is the path that will make you unhappy,
이별이 길이면 그게 널 불행하게 만들 거야,
then you shouldn't do it, Jeong-suk.
그럼 그러면 안 돼, 정숙아.
Think long and hard about it.
그것에 대해 오랫동안 열심히 생각하십시오.
No one will live your life for you.
누구도 당신을 위해 당신의 삶을 살아주지 않을 것입니다.
You know me
당신은 나를 알고
better than I know myself.
나 자신보다 더 나은.
Why do I have to quit the hospital?
왜 병원을 그만둬야 하나요?
I'll quit if you get a divorce.
이혼하면 그만둘게요.
Then you can finish your residency without problems.
그러면 레지던트를 마치시면 됩니다 문제없이.
Are you telling me
나한테 말하는 거야?
to get a divorce?
이혼하려고?
Whether I get divorced or not,
이혼하든 말든,
what gives you the right to demand that?
무엇이 당신에게 그런 것을 요구할 권리를 주나요?
"Right"?
"오른쪽"?
Then what right do you have?
그렇다면 당신에게는 어떤 권리가 있습니까?
You're the one who stole my man, got pregnant, and married him.
내 남자를 훔친 건 너야 임신해서 그 사람과 결혼했어요.
How dare you talk to me about rights?
어떻게 감히 나에게 권리에 관해 이야기하는 겁니까?
You, out of all people!
당신은 모든 사람들 중에서!
If that hadn't happened, this wouldn't have happened either!
그런 일이 일어나지 않았다면, 이런 일도 일어나지 않았을 거야!
Even when I was pregnant in the US,
미국에서 임신했을 때도
I had no intention of breaking up your family.
난 아무 의도도 없었어 가족을 깨뜨리는 것.
But come to think of it, I was being arrogant.
그런데 생각해보면, 나는 거만했다.
I didn't want to seem pathetic, so I pretended to be dignified.
한심해 보이고 싶지 않았는데, 그래서 나는 당당한 척했다.
But all that was pointless.
그러나 그 모든 것은 무의미했습니다.
I should've shamelessly snatched him away.
뻔뻔하게 그를 빼앗았어야 했는데.
Just like you did.
당신이 그랬던 것처럼요.
So your actions right now
그러니까 지금 너의 행동은
are justified?
정당합니까?
Sure, I'm not saying I did anything good.
물론, 내가 좋은 일을 했다는 말은 아니다.
But what should In-ho have done?
그런데 인호는 어떻게 했어야 했을까?
A one-night mistake resulted in a child.
하룻밤의 실수로 아이가 생겼습니다.
He left me because you got pregnant.
당신이 임신했기 때문에 그는 나를 떠났습니다.
Should he have left you because I got pregnant?
그 사람이 당신을 떠났어야 했나요? 내가 임신했기 때문에?
Is that it? Then you don't deserve redemption either.
그게 다야? 그렇다면 당신도 구원받을 자격이 없습니다.
You and I are basically the same.
당신과 나는 기본적으로 동일합니다.
So why am I the only immoral one here?
그런데 왜 여기서 부도덕한 사람은 나뿐인가요?
Why are you the only victim?
왜 당신만 피해자인가요?
I am a victim and so is my daughter!
나도 피해자이고 내 딸도 마찬가지다!
My daughter is about to give up going to college because of your daughter!
내 딸이 포기하려고 해요 딸 때문에 대학 가는 거야!
Are you satisfied now?
이제 만족하시나요?
No.
아니요.
Your daughter ending up like that
당신 딸이 결국 그렇게 됐어요
isn't enough to make me feel satisfied in this situation.
나를 만들기엔 충분하지 않아 이 상황에서 만족감을 느껴보세요.
But I do hope you realize one thing.
하지만 한 가지는 알아주셨으면 좋겠습니다.
Your daughter's unhappiness is the price of your actions.
딸의 불행 당신의 행동의 대가입니다.
Don't be bitter.
씁쓸해하지 마세요.
I'll consider this the price I'm paying for my actions as well.
나는 이것을 내가 치르는 대가라고 생각하겠다 내 행동에도.
I guess you had emergency surgery.
응급수술을 받으셨나 봅니다.
A patient with panperitonitis caused by a cancer obstruction came in,
범복막염 환자 암으로 인한 장애가 들어왔습니다.
so I did the Hartmann's procedure. Thankfully, it went well.
그래서 나는 Hartmann의 절차를 수행했습니다. 고맙게도 잘 진행되었습니다.
-Keep up the good work. -Thank you.
- 계속 좋은 일을 하세요. -감사합니다.
Professor Seo.
서 교수님.
-Hello, Professor Kim. -Is something wrong?
-안녕하세요, 김교수님. - 무슨 문제라도 있는 걸까요?
A short circuit must have caused a fire in the dorms.
단락이 있어야합니다 기숙사에서 화재가 발생했습니다.
Thankfully, the security guard discovered it early,
다행히 경비원이 일찍 발견했고,
so it didn't spread much.
그래서 많이 퍼지진 않았어요.
But the smoke is really bad. It's like a tear gas chamber in there.
그런데 연기가 정말 심해요. 거기는 최루가스실과 같습니다.
I see. I'll see you later.
알겠어요. 나중에 뵙겠습니다.
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
I have to go.
나는 가야 해요.
Dr. Cha.
차 박사.
Dr. Cha, are you inside?
차 박사님, 안에 계시나요?
Dr. Cha, wake up!
차 박사님, 일어나세요!
Dr. Cha!
차 박사님!
Open the door right now!
당장 문을 열어라!
We have to get out of here.
우리는 여기서 나가야 해요.
Let's hurry out.
서둘러 나가자.
Grab onto me.
나를 붙잡아라.
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
I'll be the one to carry my wife.
나는 내 아내를 업고 갈 사람이 될 것이다.
Let go. Put me down.
가자. 나를 내려 놓으십시오.
Put me down.
나를 내려 놓으십시오.
I'm fine, so go.
난 괜찮으니 가세요.
Why was that guy with you?
그 사람이 왜 너랑 같이 있었어?
And why did you come?
그리고 왜 오셨나요?
What?
무엇?
Did you think I hit Seung-hi or something?
내가 승희씨를 때렸다고 생각했나요?
Seung-hi came here?
승희 왔어?
Yes, she unleashed her anger on me and left.
응, 그녀는 풀려났어 그녀는 나에게 분노하고 떠났습니다.
Seung-hi.
승희.
-Mom. -Hey.
-엄마. -여기요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
There's still a lot of smoke, right?
아직 연기가 많이 나죠?
It's much better than before.
이전보다 훨씬 나아졌습니다.
Hey, Mom.
안녕, 엄마.
I heard you know.
알고 계시다고 들었습니다.
About what Father did.
아버지가 하신 일에 대해서요.
Did Dr. Jeon tell you?
전 박사님께서 말씀하셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Let's talk about that later.
그것에 대해서는 나중에 이야기합시다.
I'm too weak to do it now.
나는 지금 그것을 하기에는 너무 약하다.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I just need some time.
시간이 좀 필요할 뿐이에요.
Mom, let's go to the ER together.
엄마, 같이 응급실에 가요.
You inhaled a lot of smoke, and you don't look well.
연기를 많이 들이마셨는데, 그리고 당신 안색이 안 좋아 보여요.
I got out quickly, so I didn't inhale that much.
빨리 나왔는데, 그래서 별로 흡입하지 않았어요.
I just need to rest.
난 그냥 쉬어야 해.
The dorms will be closed for three days.
기숙사는 3일간 문을 닫습니다.
They need to find out what caused the fire.
그들은 알아내야 해 무엇이 화재를 일으켰는지.
I see.
알겠어요.
Are you going to come home?
집에 올 건가요?
PROFESSOR ROY
로이 교수
I'm opening my place for free to the residents
내 자리를 무료로 공개하겠습니다 주민들에게
who lost a place to stay due to the fire.
화재로 인해 머물 곳을 잃은 사람.
It's a three-minute walk from the hospital.
도보 3분 거리 병원에서.
Unlimited bread and will be provided.
빵도 무제한이고 제공될 예정입니다.
Dr. Cha, are you feeling all right?
차박사님, 괜찮으세요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
What are you doing here at this hour?
이 시간에 여기서 뭐하세요?
The night duty room in our department is full.
야간 근무실 우리 부서는 꽉 찼어요.
I was going to check if there was room here to sleep.
확인하려고 했는데 여기에 잠잘 공간이 있었다면.
Did you not see the message?
메시지를 못 보셨나요?
Professor Roy opened up his place.
로이 교수가 자리를 열었습니다.
Still, how can I go there?
그런데 어떻게 거기로 갈 수 있나요?
Where are you going to sleep and shower?
어디서 자고 샤워할 건가요?
There's no room here.
여기에는 공간이 없습니다.
But going there is a bit…
그런데 거기 가는 게 좀…
It might be awkward to go alone,
혼자 가기엔 좀 부담스러울 수도 있지만
so let's go together.
그러니 같이 가자.
I was wondering what to do if no one came
아무도 안오면 어떡하나 고민했는데
after sending out a message like that.
그런 메시지를 보낸 후.
I sincerely welcome you both.
두 분 모두 진심으로 환영합니다.
There are two empty rooms over that way.
저쪽에 빈 방이 두 개 있어요.
You can each take one.
각자 하나씩 가져가시면 됩니다.
I'll wash up first.
나 먼저 씻을게.
The rooms are first come, first served, right?
객실은 선착순으로, 첫 번째 봉사, 그렇죠?
Of course.
물론.
How do you feel?
기분이 어때요?
You looked quite unwell before.
예전에는 몸이 꽤 안 좋아 보이셨어요.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
I guess I had a nightmare.
아무래도 악몽을 꾼 것 같아요.
Do you want a cup of tea?
차 한잔 드릴까요?
They are my parents.
그들은 나의 부모님입니다.
So when you said you were adopted…
그래서 입양됐다고 했을 땐…
It's true.
사실이에요.
They seem like good people.
그들은 좋은 사람들인 것 같습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
I was a very lucky case.
저는 정말 운이 좋은 케이스였어요.
The truth is, I'm trying to find my family here.
진실은, 저는 이곳에서 가족을 찾으려고 노력하고 있습니다.
I'm going to register my DNA first.
먼저 DNA를 등록하겠습니다.
You made a good decision.
좋은 결정을 내리셨습니다.
You have to try once so that you won't have any regrets.
한번 해봐야지 후회하지 않도록.
I wish you the best of luck.
행운을 빕니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I'll head into my room now.
이제 내 방으로 들어가겠습니다.
And thank you so much for today.
그리고 오늘 정말 감사했습니다.
I wouldn't have been able to escape without you.
난 못했을 거야 너 없이 탈출하려고.
Professor, this is your chance.
교수님, 지금이 기회입니다.
-What? -You like Dr. Cha.
-무엇? - 차 박사님을 좋아하시네요.
Me?
나?
Did you really think it wouldn't be obvious?
정말 그렇게 생각했나요? 뻔하지 않을까?
It does feel a bit immoral, but this situation is an exception.
좀 부도덕한 느낌이 들긴 하지만, 하지만 이번 상황은 예외다.
So I think it's fine.
그래서 괜찮은 것 같아요.
Go for it.
그것을 위해 가십시오.
You know that Professor Seo is cheating.
서 교수가 바람을 피우고 있는 걸 아시죠?
Well…
음…
But…
하지만…
Dr. Cha…
차 박사님…
could forgive him.
그를 용서할 수 있었습니다.
She may be a very forgiving person,
그 사람은 참으로 관대한 사람일지도 모르지만,
but it'll be hard to forgive him.
하지만 그를 용서하기는 어려울 거예요.
He has a kid.
그에게는 아이가 있습니다.
With the woman he's having an affair with.
그가 바람을 피우고 있는 여자와.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Tell your mom to come home.
엄마에게 집에 오라고 말하세요.
The dorms are closing for a few days.
며칠간 기숙사가 문을 닫습니다.
I did tell her to, but she said she wasn't going to.
나는 그녀에게 이렇게 말했어요. 하지만 그녀는 그러지 않을 거라고 하더군요.
Then where is she sleeping?
그럼 그 사람은 어디서 자고 있는 걸까요?
She said she was staying at Professor Roy's place.
그녀는 머물고 있다고 말했다 로이 교수 집에서요.
What?
무엇?
He opened up his place to any resident who has no place to go.
그는 모든 주민에게 자신의 집을 열었습니다. 갈 곳 없는 사람.
I'm sure a lot of people went.
확실히 사람들이 많이 갔더라구요.
Okay, we'll move on to the next item on the agenda.
알았어, 계속하자 의제의 다음 항목으로 이동합니다.
What Professor Roy applied for--
로이 교수가 지원한 것은--
Do you really need the devices you applied
신청한 기기가 꼭 필요한가요?
for purchase approval?
구매 승인을 위해?
Yes.
예.
If someone asks you a question,
누군가 당신에게 질문을 한다면,
shouldn't you answer with an explanation?
설명으로 대답하면 안 되나요?
It's difficult to perform a major hepatectomy
수행하기가 어렵습니다. 주요 간절제술
with the laparoscopic instruments we have now.
복강경 기구를 이용해 지금은 있습니다.
We need a laparoscopic system with 4K image quality and 3D resolution.
복강경 시스템이 필요합니다 4K 화질과 3D 해상도를 자랑합니다.
And we need an ICG camera to accurately check the resection margin
그리고 ICG 카메라가 필요해요 절제 마진을 정확하게 확인하기 위해
and to minimize bile duct injuries as much as possible.
담관 손상을 최소화하기 위해 가능한 한 많이.
You're already using a laparoscope with 3D resolution.
이미 복강경을 사용하고 계십니다. 3D 해상도로.
Perhaps you were not aware of this.
아마도 당신은 이 사실을 몰랐을 것입니다.
While it may not be an issue for GI tract surgery,
문제가 아닐 수도 있지만 위장관 수술의 경우,
it has its limits for surgery involving the liver, gallbladder, and pancreas.
수술을 포함하는 것은 한계가 있습니다 간, 담낭, 췌장.
And it has no real-time ICG conversion capability.
그리고 실시간이 없네 ICG 변환 기능.
I explained this all during the last medical meeting
이것저것 다 설명했는데 지난 의학회의 때
before I applied for approval, so I find the way you're reacting now…
제가 승인 신청을 하기 전, 그래서 지금 당신이 어떻게 반응하는지 알아냈어요…
quite troublesome.
꽤 귀찮습니다.
We bought the device only three years ago.
우리는 불과 3년 전에 그 장치를 구입했습니다.
If you request a purchase approval as soon as you come here,
구매 승인을 요청하는 경우 여기 오자마자,
what about the devices for other departments?
장치는 어때? 다른 부서에는?
You're putting the hospital director and the planning director on the spot.
병원장을 맡기시네요 그리고 그 자리에 기획이사님이 계십니다.
We have fewer patients, and the revenue stays the same even if we get new ones.
환자가 적고 수익이 새로운 것을 얻더라도 동일하게 유지됩니다.
They'll nag us!
그들은 우리에게 잔소리를 할 것이다!
Excuse me, I shall say a word.
죄송합니다만 한마디만 하겠습니다.
This here--
여기가--
That was before I came here.
내가 여기 오기 전의 일이었어.
Since I came to this hospital, a lot of things should change.
제가 이 병원에 온 이후로 많은 것이 바뀌어야 합니다.
And Professor Seo, why are you worried about that?
그리고 서교수님, 왜 그걸 걱정해요?
Not even Chief Yoon is saying anything.
윤실장도 아무 말도 하지 않는다.
What?
무엇?
Enough!
충분한!
Why are you fighting like this in a meeting?
왜 이렇게 싸우나요? 회의 중이신가요?
As doctors, you should be setting an example!
의사로서, 당신은 모범을 보여야합니다!
Yet you're glaring at each other!
그런데도 서로를 노려보고 있어요!
I'm talking right now and you're still glaring at each other!
지금 얘기 중이야 그리고 당신은 아직도 서로를 노려보고 있어요!
I was out of line during the meeting.
나는 회의 중에 줄을 서지 않았다.
I apologize.
사과드립니다.
You humiliated me publicly.
당신은 나를 공개적으로 모욕했습니다.
Yet you apologize when there's no one else around.
그래도 사과하세요 주변에 아무도 없을 때.
I know that you don't get the organizational culture
나는 당신이 얻지 못한다는 것을 알고 있습니다 조직 문화
because you lived abroad.
왜냐하면 당신은 외국에서 살았거든요.
But how could you be so rude and two-faced?
그런데 어떻게 그렇게 무례할 수가 있지? 그리고 양면?
You always look at me with contempt. But don't get the wrong idea.
당신은 항상 나를 경멸하는 눈으로 바라보고 있습니다. 하지만 잘못된 생각은 하지 마세요.
Are you that different from me?
당신은 나와 그렇게 다른가요?
At the very least…
최소한…
I didn't covet something that wasn't mine.
나는 내 것이 아닌 것을 탐내지 않았습니다.
How indecent.
얼마나 음란한가.
Yes, honey.
여보, 그래요.
You can tell me, honey.
말해도 돼, 얘야.
It's okay, just tell me.
괜찮아요, 그냥 말해 보세요.
Hello? Professor Seo?
안녕하세요? 서 교수님?
Yes, okay.
응, 알았어.
I said talk!
내가 말했지!
Right,
그렇죠,
the guardian of the patient Park Gwi-nam, who had surgery two days ago,
환자의 보호자 박귀남 님, 이틀 전에 수술을 받은 사람,
wants to see you no matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도 당신을 만나고 싶어요.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Is it that difficult to look into a patient who is in pain?
그게 그렇게 어려운 걸까 고통을 겪고 있는 환자를 살펴보려고?
Surgery doesn't solve everything!
수술로 모든 것이 해결되는 것은 아닙니다!
She's in pain after you performed the surgery!
그녀는 고통스러워 수술을 마친 후!
You should do something so she's not in pain!
당신은 뭔가를 해야 합니다 그래서 그녀는 고통스럽지 않습니다!
I understand that you're worried.
걱정하시는 것 이해합니다.
It's only been two days since her surgery, so it's natural she's in pain.
수술한지 이틀밖에 안됐는데, 그러니 그녀가 괴로워하는 것은 당연하다.
So give her medicine. She's going to die like this at her age!
그러니 그녀에게 약을 주세요. 그 나이에 이대로 죽겠구나!
We have already given her as many painkillers as we can.
우리는 이미 그녀에게 진통제를 최대한 많이.
If we give her any more
우리가 그녀에게 더 이상 주면
and cause a delay in discovering any new pains,
지연을 초래하고 새로운 고통을 발견하면서,
things may become dangerous.
상황이 위험해질 수 있습니다.
You pretend as if you care.
당신은 걱정하는 척합니다.
My aunt also underwent surgery for her colon cancer in another hospital.
이모님도 수술하셨어요 다른 병원에서 대장암 치료를 받았습니다.
But her pain was gone within a day and she was able to walk around.
하지만 하루만에 통증이 사라졌어요 그리고 그녀는 걸어다닐 수 있었습니다.
How dare you spew nonsense after screwing up the surgery?
감히 말도 안되는 소리를 내뱉다니 수술을 망친 후?
Damn it.
젠장.
The surgery went well.
수술은 잘 끝났습니다.
The level of pain that she is experiencing is
고통의 수준 그녀가 겪고 있는 일은
all within the boundaries explained in the consent form you signed.
모든 것은 경계 안에 있다 귀하가 서명한 동의서에 설명되어 있습니다.
If it gets worse,
심해지면,
we will find an appropriate painkiller to administer.
우리는 찾을 것이다 적절한 진통제를 투여합니다.
What?
무엇?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
She spat on him.
그녀는 그에게 침을 뱉었습니다.
-What? -She did what?
-무엇? - 그 사람이 무슨 짓을 했다고?
She spat on him.
그녀는 그에게 침을 뱉었습니다.
-Spat? -Really?
-말다툼? -정말?
Who?
WHO?
Oh, no.
안 돼.
What did you do this time?
이번에는 무엇을 했나요?
-I just… -No, hang on…
-난 그냥… -아니, 잠깐만…
You bit me like a coward?
겁쟁이처럼 나를 물었나요?
You pinched me like a coward?
겁쟁이처럼 날 꼬집었나요?
-I pinched you because you bit me. -I bit you because you pinched me.
- 네가 나를 물었기 때문에 나도 너를 꼬집었다. - 네가 꼬집어서 너를 물었다.
I'll send you to the ICU.
중환자실로 보내드릴게요.
What a disgrace to fight in the hospital.
병원에서 싸우는 것은 얼마나 수치스러운 일입니까?
You.
너.
Consider yourself lucky that you're still alive.
운이 좋다고 생각하세요 당신이 아직 살아 있다는 걸요.
If you contact Bong-suk one more time,
봉숙이한테 한 번 더 연락하면
all bets are off.
모든 베팅이 종료되었습니다.
I told you already.
나는 이미 말했다.
Bong-suk texted me first.
봉석이가 먼저 문자를 보냈어요.
At least, today.
적어도 오늘은요.
Whether it's a text or call, don't answer it. Block her!
문자든 전화든, 대답하지 마세요. 그녀를 차단하세요!
Don't order me around. It's not your business!
나에게 명령하지 마세요. 그것은 당신의 사업이 아닙니다!
You betrayed her to marry into a rich household.
당신은 결혼하려고 그녀를 배신했어요 부유한 집으로.
How dare you sway her?
어떻게 감히 그녀를 흔들 수 있나요?
You filthy bacteria.
더러운 박테리아야.
Bacteria? You little…
박테리아? 너 좀…
You virus, how dare you meddle?
바이러스야, 어떻게 감히 간섭해?
Why would you meddle in our ardent love?
왜 우리의 뜨거운 사랑에 간섭하려 합니까?
You're not her father!
당신은 그 사람의 아버지가 아니잖아요!
I'm practically like her father.
나는 거의 그녀의 아버지와 같습니다.
My father told me not to associate with the likes of you on his deathbed.
아버지는 나에게 어울리지 말라고 하셨다 당신과 같은 사람들이 그의 임종을 앞두고 있습니다.
Your father died when you were young, before we even met.
네 아버지는 네가 어렸을 때 돌아가셨고, 우리가 만나기도 전에.
I should sew your lips shut with a needle!
바늘로 입술을 꿰매야겠어!
-I'll punch you! Three times! -I'll do it two times!
- 때릴게요! 세 번! - 두 번 할게요!
-I'll do it four times! Six times! -I'll do it five times!
- 네 번 할게요! 여섯 번! - 다섯 번 할게요!
Please be quiet!
조용히 해주세요!
This punk called me "bacteria."
그 새끼는 나를 "박테리아"라고 불렀어요.
I held back. I was going to call you "cancer."
나는 참았다. 나는 당신을 "암"이라고 부르려고 했어요.
You punk, you're divorced with two kids.
이 멍청아, 당신은 아이 둘과 이혼했잖아.
My younger sister is still unwed, so how dare you!
여동생은 아직 미혼이고, 그러니 어떻게 감히!
Calm down. You two being like this--
진정하다. 너희 둘이 이렇게-
You two being like this won't solve anything.
너희 둘이 이러고 있어 아무것도 해결되지 않습니다.
That's exactly what I was saying.
내가 말한 것이 바로 그것이다.
So…
그래서…
Chief Yoon.
윤 과장.
What will you do now?
이제 무엇을 하시겠습니까?
If Bong-suk forgives me,
봉석이가 나를 용서해준다면
I want to start over with her.
나는 그녀와 함께 다시 시작하고 싶다.
Chief Lim.
임 과장.
If your younger sister forgives him,
여동생이 그를 용서한다면,
it's fate, and all is well--
이건 운명이고, 다 괜찮을 거야--
What do you mean by forgive?
용서한다는 게 무슨 뜻인가요?
Bong-suk told me she's still thinking about it!
봉석이가 말했어 그녀는 아직도 그것에 대해 생각하고 있어요!
Things were going well with the attorney she met!
일이 잘 진행되고 있었어 그녀가 만난 변호사와 함께!
Wouldn't you try to stop this?
이걸 막으려 하지 않겠습니까?
If that person is precious to me,
그 사람이 나에게 소중한 사람이라면
I would.
나는 그럴 것이다.
I would cheer on her new love.
그녀의 새로운 사랑을 응원하겠습니다.
A man who betrays someone once can betray them again.
한 번 배신한 남자 그들을 다시 배신할 수 있습니다.
-Right. -Dr. Roy, you punk!
-오른쪽. -박사. 로이, 이 새끼야!
What will you do if Bong-suk forgives him?
봉석이 그를 용서한다면 당신은 어떻게 할 것인가?
Love…
사랑…
lasts forever.
영원히 지속됩니다.
Doesn't love change?
사랑은 변하지 않는가?
It did so for you.
그것은 당신을 위해 그랬습니다.
You're all ready.
모두 준비되었습니다.
Hello, you're here. Dr. Roy dropped by too.
안녕하세요, 당신은 여기에 있습니다. 로이 박사님도 들렀어요.
My patient is being discharged, so I should come.
내 환자는 퇴원 중이고, 그래서 내가 와야 해.
-Did you go see the baby today too? -Yes.
- 오늘도 아기 보러 가셨나요? -예.
She's so pretty.
그녀는 너무 예뻐요.
How can I leave her here?
어떻게 그녀를 여기에 두고 갈 수 있나요?
The baby may seem like an angel now,
이제 아기는 천사처럼 보일지도 모르지만,
but once you raise her, it's harder than you think.
하지만 일단 키우면 생각보다 어렵습니다.
Right, ma'am?
그렇죠 부인?
But they say no mother regrets giving birth to their child.
하지만 엄마는 후회하지 않는다고 하던데 자녀를 낳습니다.
You're preparing for her first birthday already?
준비하고 계시네요 벌써 첫 생일이었어?
-Yes. -Jeez, don't even get me started.
-예. - 이런, 시작도 하지 마세요.
She's already reserving the food and trying to order the clothes.
그 사람은 이미 음식을 예약하고 있어 그리고 옷을 주문하려고 해요.
Jeez, you're the epitome of an overzealous mother.
이런, 당신은 전형이에요 지나치게 열성적인 어머니의 모습.
She takes after you.
그녀는 당신을 닮아갑니다.
Dr. Seo, what item did you grab on your first birthday?
서 박사님, 어떤 물건을 쥐셨나요? 첫 번째 생일에?
Me?
나?
I…
나는…
Dr. Seo
서 박사
grabbed a pencil.
연필을 잡았다.
To tell you the truth, he's my son.
사실을 말하자면, 그 사람은 내 아들이에요.
-Oh, my.
-아, 이런.
Really?
정말?
-What in the world? -You look alike!
-세상에 무슨 일이요? -닮았네요!
-We do, right? -Yes.
- 그렇죠? -예.
He resembles his father.
그는 그의 아버지를 닮았다.
I see.
알겠어요.
-Then Dr. Seo, can I ask you for a favor? -Sure.
-그럼 서 박사님, 부탁 하나 해도 될까요? -확신하는.
I'm going to prepare a really strong ball of yarn.
준비할게 정말 강한 실 공.
But for the pencil, they say it's good to use one
하지만 연필의 경우, 하나쓰는게 좋다고 하던데
that was used by a smart person.
똑똑한 사람이 사용한 것입니다.
I see. Would a ballpoint pen work too?
알겠어요. 볼펜도 괜찮을까요?
Is it okay to accept this?
이거 받아도 괜찮나요?
Yes.
예.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Get home safely.
집에 안전하게 도착하세요.
-Mom, give that to me. -No.
-엄마, 그거 나한테 주세요. -아니요.
Give it. I'll carry it.
줘. 내가 가지고 다닐게.
I hope she makes it to the baby's first birthday.
나는 그녀가 성공하길 바라 아기의 첫 번째 생일에.
She will.
그녀는 그럴 것입니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Didn't your dad give you that pen as a gift?
아빠가 안줬어? 그 펜을 선물로 주나요?
For when you got into med school.
네가 의과대학에 입학했을 때 말이야.
Yes.
예.
It doesn't matter.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I'll get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
Hello, Cha Jeong-suk speaking.
안녕하세요, 차정숙입니다.
What?
무엇?
That's dangerous. Hey, guys!
그건 위험해요. 안녕, 얘들아!
Stop it!
그만해요!
Get this bastard.
이 놈을 잡아라.
-Stop! This is a hospital! -No way.
-멈추다! 여기는 병원이에요! -안 돼요.
It can't be!
그럴 리가 없어!
-I told you to stop! -Oh, my!
-내가 그만하라고 했잖아! -아, 이런!
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
-I said stop!
-그만하라고 했어!
-You two must be crazy! -Come on!
-너희 둘은 미쳤나봐! -어서 해봐요!
What's with you? I thought you were all about maintaining your image.
무슨 일이세요? 나는 당신이 그럴 줄 알았는데 이미지 유지에 관한 모든 것.
Defend yourself. Otherwise, you might end up on the chopping block.
자신을 방어하세요. 그렇지 않으면 결국 도마 위에 올라가게 됩니다.
Someone always has to be held accountable.
누군가는 항상 책임을 져야 합니다.
Hey, Seo In-ho!
안녕하세요, 서인호님!
It's annoying to the point of driving me crazy,
요점까지 짜증나네요 나를 미치게 만들다니,
so hurry up and leave.
그러니 서둘러서 떠나세요.
You must have lost your mind.
정신을 잃었나 봐요.
If you say we should break up, I'm going to kill you.
헤어지자고 하면 나는 당신을 죽일 것입니다.
I'll wait until you finish your meal.
당신이 식사를 마칠 때까지 기다릴게요.
Let's get a divorce.
이혼하자
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-ji Chi
자막번역 : 지윤지